<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Saumya</title>
    <link>https://saumya.github.io/2021/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Saumya</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 17:34:35 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://saumya.github.io/2021/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>React 17. FastRefresh, not HotReload.</title>
      <link>https://saumya.github.io/2021/posts/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 17:34:35 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saumya.github.io/2021/posts/4/</guid>
      <description>A must upgrade version of React is React 17. I was surprised by the things it brings to the equation.
 I was working on a project which is old. Not so old but kind of not recent also. And we just pushed our production application to live environment.
 At that point I have some time to update the project. So I did. The first upgrade I thought should be the React library itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project went live.</title>
      <link>https://saumya.github.io/2021/posts/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 15:35:07 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saumya.github.io/2021/posts/3/</guid>
      <description>For last 5 months, I was working on a new project. Finally it went live last week.
 It is such an experience to be involved in this kind of projects.
 In terms of frontend technology it is React through and through. It was a re-write of the old project. The project has a global reach and directly affects people. Whatever we are doing has a direct effect on the general people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo &amp; Paths</title>
      <link>https://saumya.github.io/2021/posts/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 18:21:25 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saumya.github.io/2021/posts/2/</guid>
      <description>Hugo is fast and just works. However there are certain things you must take into consideration while hosting it.
Till now one thing I came across is the path for css files. Hugo provides template short codes to deal with them.
 The templating system cares for empty spaces in the template.
 You should be extra careful not to put them. For example href=&amp;quot;{{ .Site.BaseURL }}css/2021.css&amp;quot; and href=&amp;quot;{{ .Site.BaseURL }} css/2021.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Again.</title>
      <link>https://saumya.github.io/2021/posts/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 21:52:12 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saumya.github.io/2021/posts/1/</guid>
      <description>A long wait is finally over.
For a long long time I was lazy and was avoiding the work. But here it is.
Moved to the Hugo Engine from Wintersmith Engine.
Never thought I will continue this way. But this is good to start over and over again. This is life if one wants to live. Re-start, Re-build, Re-structure and keep living.
The last blog is here for the new visitors here.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
