<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Saumya</title>
    <link>https://saumya.github.io/2021/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Saumya</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 20:30:19 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://saumya.github.io/2021/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Product or Technology</title>
      <link>https://saumya.github.io/2021/posts/22/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 20:30:19 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saumya.github.io/2021/posts/22/</guid>
      <description>This is always the case. It is always OR never AND.
There are talks about how technology is the key to a successful product. May be it is true in the beginning, till one has to maintain it. Almost all successful products in the market are not of the latest technolgy. There are some parts of it is new technology, but majority is old, very old. The technology they use are once new, but now it is old and that is ok.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working with YARN</title>
      <link>https://saumya.github.io/2021/posts/21/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 10:59:17 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saumya.github.io/2021/posts/21/</guid>
      <description>Working in Yarn was a little involved. That is Yarn version 1. One has to play around with Node and NPM to make things setup. With Yarn version 2 and above, this is mostly done by Node and a new utility called corepack.
Now, Yarn does not need to be installed as a global package. Yarn can be enabled for individual projects (individual folders).
The corepack enable is all there is to it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>React State update</title>
      <link>https://saumya.github.io/2021/posts/20/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 13:05:17 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saumya.github.io/2021/posts/20/</guid>
      <description>Updating a state in React looks something like below.
const [count, setCount] = useState(0) setCount(5) Here the new value of the count is provided to setCount. That updates the state of count to its new value.
This is the most used form of the state update.
However, there is another form of this functionality. This looks like below.
setState( previousState=&amp;gt;{ // Do Something with Previous Data // And return the newly created Data return( newState ) } ) So the code setCount(5) will become like below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>React Component and props.children</title>
      <link>https://saumya.github.io/2021/posts/19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 15:29:17 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saumya.github.io/2021/posts/19/</guid>
      <description>The game of React is in its components. Almost everything here is a component. Sooner or later the need to pass properties to components will arise. This is straight forward as we know like this.
&amp;lt;MyComp myTitle=&amp;#39;Nice Component&amp;#39; /&amp;gt; Inside component we can access this with props.myTitle.
const MyComp = (props)=&amp;gt;{	return( &amp;lt;div&amp;gt; { props.myTitle } &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt; ) } This can also be written as below.
const MyComp = ( {myTitle} )=&amp;gt;{	return( &amp;lt;div&amp;gt; { myTitle } &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt; ) } There is a nice magic props that React has, on all the components.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing Component Code in ReactJS</title>
      <link>https://saumya.github.io/2021/posts/18/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 11:27:24 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saumya.github.io/2021/posts/18/</guid>
      <description>React defines and speculates about how to manage code files for components. There are so many documentation and tools available as per the best practices and perfect scenaios. However as per my experience no perfect scenario ever worked for any individual or company.
There is difference between perfect scenario and working scenario.
While everyone should try to stick to the best practices and perfect scenarios, it is a perpetual job. It never ends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu 22.04</title>
      <link>https://saumya.github.io/2021/posts/17/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 22:08:27 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saumya.github.io/2021/posts/17/</guid>
      <description>My working machine is a Linux machine for some years now.
I never felt this kind of freedom and productive before. Now I can say it is even better than MacOS in terms of developer freedom and easiness. It is better than Windows in terms of GUI applications. The time has gone when Linux used to be command only. Today the GUI applications are much better in Linux than Windows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SVG on Web</title>
      <link>https://saumya.github.io/2021/posts/16/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 13:06:42 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saumya.github.io/2021/posts/16/</guid>
      <description>SVG is fine jsut to know it as an image format.
However, to deal with SVG on a web application as a developer is a different thing. SVG is too generic for better or worse as Javascript. Unless you know your way through it, it might seem confusing or easy.
First is there are many ways to include SVG in web.
The basic is just the tag itself. It is a valid HTML tag.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VIM Plugin NERDTree</title>
      <link>https://saumya.github.io/2021/posts/15/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2022 22:17:37 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saumya.github.io/2021/posts/15/</guid>
      <description>Installing a VIM plugin in Ubuntu is not that complicated as it used to be. All one has to do is put the plugin in a proper folder. However, do not confuse yourself VIM with VI. By default Ubuntu comes installed with VI and not VIM. Even if you put the VIM plugin in the proper place, it will not reflect in this editor.
First install VIM.
For Ubuntu it is just sudo apt install vim.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alpine JS</title>
      <link>https://saumya.github.io/2021/posts/14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 15:18:23 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saumya.github.io/2021/posts/14/</guid>
      <description>In the noisy space of Javascript and Javascript Frameworks, this one is nice and quiet. The simplicity of this framework dragged me into it. This happens to me for a new framework which does the thing and keeps it simple. Same thing happened to me when React came in. Appart from its corporate backing, it did work for a couple of years. As usual slowly complexity built arround it. I am afraid Alpine might go that route.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Copying folder with Python</title>
      <link>https://saumya.github.io/2021/posts/13/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 22:21:04 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saumya.github.io/2021/posts/13/</guid>
      <description>Python is powerful like anyother programming language. However the simplicity of it makes it more beautiful.
I was trying to automate some of my tasks and this needed copying of a folder with all its files and folders and files inside those folders to a new location. With Python it just took some lines and the task is done!
import shutil
shutil.copytree(source_folder, destination_folder, dirs_exist_ok = True)
The shutil is a utility to deal with file operations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting different Yarn versions in Ubuntu / Linux</title>
      <link>https://saumya.github.io/2021/posts/12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 14:51:16 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saumya.github.io/2021/posts/12/</guid>
      <description>This should be a one liner as per the Yarn Docs.
It doesnot work always like that.
The problem This happens if you have installed the latest version of Yarn. Then and only then one can change Yarn versions. After installing the latest version of Yarn, we can use the old version by setting Yarn to older version.
yarn set version classic
The classic version is 1.x version.
At this point we are good for our projects which use Yarn version 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reviving my MacBookPro</title>
      <link>https://saumya.github.io/2021/posts/11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 12:21:01 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saumya.github.io/2021/posts/11/</guid>
      <description>The thing is, Apple does not care about anything else but money.
Apple products are good. They work as Apple expects them to work. People just follow along and pride themselves for having an Apple device. The products die when Apple wants them to die. Now my device, MacBookPro which is still good in terms of Hardware, Apple software does not get updated in this. As per Apple the device needs an upgrade.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Powerline Fish</title>
      <link>https://saumya.github.io/2021/posts/10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 22:43:48 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saumya.github.io/2021/posts/10/</guid>
      <description>Powerline is a wonderful utility apart from visually pleasing shell prompts.
In the early days it was a whole lot of effort to install and apply it to Linux / Ubuntu. However the situations have changed. Now it is
sudo apt install powerline and there you have it.
Now to add this to Fish, the best way is to use Oh My Fish. Once Oh My Fish is installed, enable bobthefish theme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.bashrc / .bash_profile</title>
      <link>https://saumya.github.io/2021/posts/9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 20:34:31 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saumya.github.io/2021/posts/9/</guid>
      <description>Setting up any UNIX like system comes down to a single startup file. There could be many, if one wants to, the freedom is always there. But generally it starts at a single point.
OSX / MacOS In this land the file is .bash_profile. Almost all the things can be configured here.
UBUNTU / Linux Here the file is .bashrc. All the PATH and systemwide settings reside here.
Both of these files stay in the root of the user home folder in both MacOS and UBUNTU.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021 Retrospect.</title>
      <link>https://saumya.github.io/2021/posts/8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 16:17:25 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saumya.github.io/2021/posts/8/</guid>
      <description>The year started slow but kept up the steadiness. There were a lot of endings and new beginnings. As always if it flows, it is life.
Tech and work A new project started.
For a long long time I was in a stealth mode. Bootstrapping and failing, then start over again and fail. The cycle finally ended. There are huge experience gain in terms of building a product and selling it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vite it.</title>
      <link>https://saumya.github.io/2021/posts/7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Nov 2021 11:45:53 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saumya.github.io/2021/posts/7/</guid>
      <description>The natural progress of the frontend tooling. Whether you like it or not, change is here to stay. At the moment the frontend frameworks have reached a point, where we need something else to have a better Developer Experience.
Applications were always like this and will remain like this.
What could change is how we write these applications. Divisions have been made to separate the concerns. However in frontend, we had put very little effort in terms of development for a long long time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code to throw away.</title>
      <link>https://saumya.github.io/2021/posts/6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 21:57:20 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saumya.github.io/2021/posts/6/</guid>
      <description>The thing that is fixed in code is the change. While lot of books and philosophy is done towards how to reuse the code, very little is focused towards the change!
The reality of the life of the code is very different from the literature around it.
All the reusabilty and other thoughts look good in books. In reality I have hardly seen any code is re-used. This is not to diminish the reusabilty of the code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single knowledge base</title>
      <link>https://saumya.github.io/2021/posts/5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 09:46:30 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saumya.github.io/2021/posts/5/</guid>
      <description>The age old problem which repeats itself is, how to make a single code base for a project which is delivered to multiple platforms?!
Many tachnologies has come and promised the same thing. The end result is to enter the corporate space. Why!? Money.
This is the true story of all the technology stacks which promise to have a single codebase. Some really nice technologies has come and stayed for good, some vanished without leaving a trace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>React 17. FastRefresh, not HotReload.</title>
      <link>https://saumya.github.io/2021/posts/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 17:34:35 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saumya.github.io/2021/posts/4/</guid>
      <description>A must upgrade version of React is React 17. I was surprised by the things it brings to the equation.
I was working on a project which is old. Not so old but kind of not recent also. And we just pushed our production application to live environment.
At that point I have some time to update the project. So I did. The first upgrade I thought should be the React library itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project went live.</title>
      <link>https://saumya.github.io/2021/posts/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 15:35:07 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saumya.github.io/2021/posts/3/</guid>
      <description>For last 5 months, I was working on a new project. Finally it went live last week.
It is such an experience to be involved in this kind of projects.
In terms of frontend technology it is React through and through. It was a re-write of the old project. The project has a global reach and directly affects people. Whatever we are doing has a direct effect on the general people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo &amp; Paths</title>
      <link>https://saumya.github.io/2021/posts/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 18:21:25 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saumya.github.io/2021/posts/2/</guid>
      <description>Hugo is fast and just works. However there are certain things you must take into consideration while hosting it.
Till now one thing I came across is the path for css files. Hugo provides template short codes to deal with them.
The templating system cares for empty spaces in the template.
You should be extra careful not to put them. For example href=&amp;quot;{{ .Site.BaseURL }}css/2021.css&amp;quot; and href=&amp;quot;{{ .Site.BaseURL }} css/2021.css&amp;quot; are different.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Again.</title>
      <link>https://saumya.github.io/2021/posts/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 21:52:12 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saumya.github.io/2021/posts/1/</guid>
      <description>A long wait is finally over.
For a long long time I was lazy and was avoiding the work. But here it is.
Moved to the Hugo Engine from Wintersmith Engine.
Never thought I will continue this way. But this is good to start over and over again. This is life if one wants to live. Re-start, Re-build, Re-structure and keep living.
The last blog is here for the new visitors here.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
